# Tayrone Monteiro

### Computer Engineer

I have a deep passion for solving biological problems through statistics, programming and data analysis. Also, I have over four years of experience in scientific research. Currently seeking a position in which I can use my solid problem-solving skills.





tayronesm@gmail.com

+55 83 998229901



Patos, PB, Brazil

In linkedin.com/in/tayronem



github.com/tayrone

## **SKILLS**

Tidyverse

Python

Unix

Shell Scripting

Git/Github

Statistics

Machine Learning

Power BI

## SOFT SKILLS

Creativity

Critical Thinking

Attention to Detail

Emotional Intelligence

Interpersonal Skills

## **EDUCATION**

### **MSc in Bioinformatics**

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte

03/2019 - 08/2021

Natal, Brazil

### Undergraduate Academic Exchange

Milwaukee School of Engineering

08/2015 - 05/2016

Milwaukee, USA

### **BSc in Computer Engineering**

Federal University of Paraíba

03/2012 - 12/2017

João Pessoa, Brazil

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Full-length paper

## The Paulo Freire Digital Library indexing method as a tool for digital fluency

Santos R., Monteiro T., Brennand E., Silva O.

Revista Informação na Sociedade Contemporânea, n.1, 2014.

Full-length paper

## The interactive television as a device for digital inclusion in higher education

**Authors** 

Brennand E., Monteiro T.

Conference

Colóquio Internacional de Pesquisas na Educação Superior. João Pessoa, Brazil. 2013.

## **LANGUAGES**

Portuguese

Enalish

Native

Full Professional Proeficiency

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Researcher

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte

03/2019 - 08/2021

Natal, Brazil

Responsibilities and outcomes

- Analyze microarray expression and methylation data of medulloblastoma cancer patients, using R;
- Examine additional attributes, such as coregulation mechanisms and survival probability, for all cases:
- Produce a scientific paper describing all inspections and results, such as biological markers and their relation to clinical outcomes:

#### Research Assistant

University of Notre Dame

05/2016 - 07/2016

South Bend, USA

Responsibilities and outcomes

- Implemented local and global sequence alignment algorithms, using C;
- Applied these methods to compare genetic information from several bacteria genomes, defining phylogenetic proximity between different species:

### Research Assistant

Federal University of Paraíba

08/2013 - 07/2015

João Pessoa, Brazil

Responsibilities and outcomes

- Implemented clustering algorithms, such as Mean Shift and Expectation Maximization, using Java:
- Applied clustering methods on bacterial genomic data, resulting in the identification of novel genomic islands. This work evolved to become my senior thesis:
- Managed a relational database, associated with a digital library, using the SQL language;
- Created a graphical user interface model, for an educational software, using a graphic design application (Sketch).